JAMES BROADHEAD

Electronic and Computer Engineer

jamesbroadhead@gmail.com

careers.stackoverflow.com/jamesbroadhead

+44 741 342 0400 (UTC)

I contribute to **Gentoo Linux** and my preferred language is **Python**, but I have experience with **C**, **Java** and **Erlang**. I am active in developing my skills, attending user-groups and keeping up to date watching conference presentations and trying out new tools and libraries.

Recent Activity:

Practising TDD for Django with unittest and selenium Reading 'Expert Python Programming' Updating the Fox toolkit in Gentoo, build-script fixes

Experience:

2011 - BSB Ireland Software Developer

2011-12 International Software Development team, developing Life Insurance / Financial software in Java.

Involved in bug-fixing, feature development and code review Server-client model with object persistence.

Key Technologies: *Java, Spring, Maven, Jboss, Junit, Oracle, SQL, svn, hg*

2007 - 2010 Telecommunications Research Group (Trinity College Dublin) Postgraduate Researcher

Developed Distributed Simulation Framework for Monte-Carlo Simulation and Statistical Analysis of Frequency Rendezvous using Python and C.

Profiling and Optimisation as project developed and research needs changed, replacing Python with With C modules and SciPy calls based on profiling with psyco

Project management / Bug Tracking / VCS - TRAC, Subversion

Attended International Conferences and Workshops, Involved in Peer Review of submitted papers

Taught First-Year Engineering class for Digital Design project

Key Technologies: *Python, C (PyObject), SciPy, Numpy, multiprocessing,*



JAMES BROADHEAD

Experience (cont.):

2007 (4mo.) Cisco Systems Software Development Engineering Intern

> Software Development Internship in San Jose with individual tasks and deadlines on two projects.

Programming VOIP client in C++ using Windows API and MFC.

Key Technologies: *Visual C++, MFC, Windows API, C++test, SIP, Clearcase*

2006 (3mo.) Xilinx Customer Applications Engineering Intern

> Debugging customer design issues using VHDL, Verilog, attending digital design courses, and design work.

Experience dealing with remote team and customers over telephone, instant-message and remote-desktop

Key Technologies: VHDL, Verilog, Circuitry-level Optimisation

2005 - pres. Gentoo Linux User / Contributor

> Active member of community; submitting bug reports, patches, and install scripts. I contribute to documentation and help in the user support channel.

> Maintain personal systems each with custom compiler optimisations and hand-configured kernels. Minor kernel patching.

Build-system and System administration experience, debugging failed builds and failing applications with gdb, strace.

Maintain minor forks of two projects with patches that have not yet been merged upstream.

Key Technologies: *gcc, gdb, strace, Bugzilla, Mercurial, python, bash*

Education:

2007 Baccalaureus in Arte Ingeniaria (B.A.I) Hons.

> Bachelor of Computer and Electronic Engineering Trinity College Dublin

2003 Leaving Certificate, St. Andrew's College, Co. Dublin

A2 (85-90%) Maths, English, Music, French

B2 (75-80%) Irish,

B3 (70-75%) Physics, Classical Studies.

Other Experience:

2002 - 2010 Reserve Defence Force: Infantry Platoon Sergeant (Part-time)

Leadership/Training/Administration role for 30 soldiers.

English, French, Irish Languages:

Interests: Music; Grade 8 Oboe, Reading, Sailing, Skiing, Hiking, Reading.